{"tossups": [{"question": "Yigal Yadin excavated this site, which can be approached via the \"Snake Path\". Josephus recorded a speech by this site's defender in which he ordered that a banquet be set. This site,  which new recruits into the Israeli army vow \u201cshall not fall again\u201d was besieged by the Tenth Legion and it was the last holdout of the Zealots. For 10 points, name this giant rock mesa on which Eliezer ben Jair's followers supposedly committed suicide rather than be captured by the Romans.", "answer": "<b><u>Masada</u></b> [muh-SAH-duh]  [Doug Grae<u>bner]</u>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "An empire named for this region was founded by Postumus and destroyed by Emperor Aurelian. In this region, contravallation and circumvallation fortifications were built around a city held by Commius. A war in this region was ended at the Siege of Alesia when the Romans captured the Avernian chief Vercingetorix [ver-sin-GET-oh-ricks]. A book describing the conquest of this region opens by noting that it is \"divided into three parts.\" For 10 points, name this region conquered by Julius Caesar, which roughly corresponds to modern-day France.", "answer": "<b><u>Gaul</u></b> [or <b><u>Gallia</u></b>]  [Jordan Bro<u>wnst</u>ein]", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "A name used to describe these objects was first coined by the English philosopher Thomas Wright and was later used by Kant to describe so-called \u201cnebulous objects\u201d in the heavens. The \u201cGreat Debate\u201d concerning the distance to these objects pitted Harlow Shapley against Heber  Curtis. The distance to these \u201cisland universes\u201d was calculated through observations by Hubble.  For 10 points, name these giant groups of stars, examples of which include the Milky Way.", "answer": "<b><u>galaxies</u></b> [or <b><u>galaxy</u></b>; accept more specific answers, like <b><u>spiral galaxies</u></b> or <b><u>elliptical</u></b> <b><u>galaxies</u></b>; pr<u>ompt on</u> <b><u>isla</u><u>nd uni</u><u>verse</u></b>s until it is read but do not accept or prompt on \u201cuniverses\u201d <u>alone]</u>  [Sriram Pendyala]", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Astronomy"}, {"question": "This man composed four anthems, including <em>Zadok the Priest</em>, for various coronations. He included \"La Paix\" [pay] and \"La Rejouissance\" [ray-zhoo-ee-sahnss] in a piece that celebrates the end of the War of the Austrian Succession. Another of his compositions was written for George I, who requested a concert on the River Thames [temz]. Those works by this man are <em>Music for the Royal Fireworks</em> and <em>Water Music</em>. For 10 points, name this German-British composer whose oratorio <em>Messiah</em> includes the \"Hallelujah\" chorus.", "answer": "George Frideric <b><u>Handel</u></b> [or Georg Friedrich <b><u>H\u00e4ndel</u></b>] [Eddie Kim]", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This man served as the chair of the Senate Judiciary Committee during the Robert Bork hearings. After after sharing confidential details from a conversation with President Erdogan [AIR-doh-ahn] in October 2014, he was forced to officially apologize to Turkey. He was forced to drop out of the 1988 Presidential election after plagiarizing a Neil Kinnock speech. <em>The Onion</em> created parody \u201cDiamond\u201d and \u201cUncle\u201d versions of this current politician. For 10 points, name this gaffe-prone current Vice President of the United States.", "answer": "Joe <b><u>Biden</u></b> [or Joseph Robinette <b><u>Biden</u></b>, Jr.]  [Erik Owen]", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "Right-wing supporters of this man murdered left-wingers at an airport in the Ezeiza [ehz-eh-EE-zah] massacre. He fled on a gunboat provided by Alfredo Stroessner after he was overthrown in a coup called the \u201cLiberating Revolution\u201d. This person came to power with the help of the so-called \u201cshirtless ones\u201d, or <em>descamisados</em> [dess-cah-mi-SAH-doze], and was initially succeeded by his third wife after his death. For 10 points, name this predecessor of Jorge Videla, an Argentinian dictator who was married to Isabel and Eva, or \u201cEvita\u201d.", "answer": "Juan Domingo <b><u>Per\u00f3n</u> </b> [Jason Zhou]", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The ruling in this case disagreed with a previous case centering on the <em>Antelope</em>. Joseph Story's majority decision in this case agreed that the Adams-Onis and Pinckney's Treaties did not apply to its defendants, since they were never legal property. This case\u2019s defendants were represented by Roger Sherman Baldwin and John Quincy Adams. For 10 points, name this 1841 case that resulted from a slave mutiny on a ship in Cuba.", "answer": "<em><b><u>Amistad</u></b></em> case [or <em>United States v. Libellants and Claimants of the Schooner</em> <em><b><u>Amistad</u></b></em>] [Kenji Goli<u>mlim]</u>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This city merged with the surrounding towns of Southwark and Northern Liberties in an 1854 Act of Consolidation. Its Fairmount Water Works replaced an earlier system in Center  Square. This city\u2019s City Hall was the tallest building in the world from its construction until 1908, and is topped with a statue of its founder. For 10 points, name this city founded by William Penn between the Schuylkill [skoo-kill] and Delaware Rivers, where the Declaration of Independence was signed.", "answer": "<b><u>Philadelphia</u></b>, Pennsylvania  [Christophe<u>r White]</u>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man signed America\u2019s first \u201cstand your ground\u201d law in 2005. He recently advised donors to contribute no more than 1 million dollars each to his PACs, and delivered a speech advocating  a \u201cright to rise\u201d to the Detroit Economic Club in February. This man met his wife Columba while  teaching English in Mexico. Secretary of State Katherine Harris led the 2000 presidential recount in the state this man governed. For 10 points, name this two-term governor of Florida and potential 2016 Republican candidate for President, the younger brother of George W.", "answer": "<b><u>J</u></b>eb <b><u>Bush</u></b> [or <b><u>J</u></b>ohn Ellis <b><u>Bush</u></b>; prompt on \u201cBush\u201d]  [Christophe<u>r</u> W<u>hite]</u>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This tournament is officially named for a World War I aviator who put metal plates on his propeller to safely shoot a machine gun though it. Max Decugis [DEH-coo-gee] held a record eight singles titles at this event until that record was broken in 2014. The winningest champion at this second of the four Grand Slam events has won it in nine of the past ten years; that player is Spain\u2019s Rafael Nadal [nuh-DALL]. For 10 points, name this only tennis Grand Slam tournament played on clay, which is held in continental Europe.", "answer": "<b><u>French Open</u></b> [or the <b><u>Roland Garros</u></b>; or Les <b><u>internationaux de France</u></b> de Tennis, Roland Gar<u>ros; or Tourno</u>i de <b><u>Rol</u><u>and-Garros</u></b><u>]</u>  [Patrick Liao] <b>SECOND QUARTER</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {}, {"question": "Zappo Zaps were used to collect taxes in this modern-day nation. Mark Twain wrote a satirical \u201csoliloquy\u201d skewering the ruler of a colony in this modern-day nation. The Casement Report detailed terrible abuse of natives forced to harvest rubber in this nation, which inspired <em>Heart of Darkness</em>. For 10 points, name this modern nation, which was originally the personal African colony of King Leopold II of Belgium.", "answer": "Democratic Republic of the <b><u>Congo</u></b> [or <b><u>DRC</u></b>; or <b><u>Congo Free State</u></b>; prompt on <b><u>Zaire</u></b>]  <u>BON</u>US: King Leopold used this British explorer, who fought on both sides in the US Civil War, to explore and claim the Congo. He is better-known for finding Dr. Livingstone. ANSWER: Henry Morton <b><u>Stanley</u></b> [or John <b><u>Rowlands</u></b>]  [Bruce Arthur]", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "According to Herodotus [heh-ROD-uh-tuss], the earliest usage of these things occurred under the rule of Alyattes [ahl-YAH-tees] in Lydia, where they were made with <em>electrum</em>. The <em>solidus</em> was one of these items whose usage was introduced by Diocletian [dye-oh-CLEE-shun]. The field of numismatics studies these objects, which in the Roman Empire included <em>asses</em>, <em>sestertii</em> [sess-TER-shee], and <em>denarii</em>. For 10 points, identify these typically round, metal objects used as currency.", "answer": "<b><u>coin</u></b>s [accept <b><u>token</u></b>s or anything mentioning <b><u>money</u></b>]", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "With Cauchy [COH-shee], this person names a pair of equations that determine whether a function is holomorphic. This man\u2019s method of integration was improved by Lebesgue [luh-BEG]. That method of integration uses rectangles to approximate a curve with his namesake sum. For 10 points, identify this mathematician whose \u201cHypothesis\u201d is one of the Millenium Prize Problems.", "answer": "Bernhard <b><u>Riemann</u></b> [REE-mahn]", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Math"}, {}, {"question": "At various times, this man used the pseudonyms \"Otto Heninger\" and \"Ricardo Klement.\" The phrase \"banality of evil\" was used to describe this man\u2019s actions in a book by Hannah Arendt. This man, who was placed in a glass box during his trial, became the only person ever executed in Israel after he was captured in Buenos Aires. For 10 points, name this Nazi responsible for the logistics of the Holocaust.", "answer": "Adolf <b><u>Eichmann</u> </b>", "metadata": "Literature - European Literature - Misc Literature"}, {}, {"question": "An employee of this organization incited the Pyramid Lake War, and it was founded by Russell, Majors, and Waddell. Its employees carried a colt revolver and a Bible with them. This initiative's stopping points included Fort Laramie and Carson City. It only ran from 1860 to 1861. For 10 points, name this institution which physically transported mail from Missouri to California on horseback.", "answer": "<b><u>Pony Express</u> </b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Coalition forces in this war bombed Highway 80 into the so-called Highway of Death. This war is the namesake of a \u201csyndrome\u201d that some have linked to sarin gas. This war was launched in response to an invasion of Kuwait the previous year. For 10 points, name this 1990 to 1991 war that included Operations Desert Shield and Desert Storm in which a US- led coalition fought Saddam Hussein.", "answer": "the First Persian <b><u>Gulf</u></b> War [or the <b><u>Kuwait</u></b> War; prompt on <b><u>Operation Desert Shield</u> </b>or <b><u>Operation Desert Storm</u></b><u> befo</u>re mentioned<u>]</u>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This person helped found the settlement of Portsmouth on the island of Aquidneck. This person was killed in a massacre by the Siwanoy tribe. This woman was accused of being an antinomian, and after her trial, she joined Roger Williams at his newly founded Providence Colony. For 10 points, name this Puritan who was expelled from the Massachusetts Bay Colony as a heretic.", "answer": "Anne <b><u>Hutchinson</u> </b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b><u>The Tomb of the Augurs suggests that these people played a game involving a masked</u></b> <b><u>cha</u><u>racter called Phersu, and they held councils at a sacred grove called the Fanum</u></b> <b><u>Voltumna. One artist from these successors of th</u><u>e (+) Villanovan culture was Vulc</u>a of Veii <u>[VAY-ee]. Reclining married couples, such as th</u>ose seen in the Sarcophagus of the Spouses, were common in these people's art, and Tarchon and Tyrrhenus led a (*)</b> league of twelve cities of these people. For 10 points, Tarquin the Proud was supposedly a member of what Italian civilization that preceded Rome?", "answer": "<b><u>Etruscan</u></b>s  [Chris Chie<u>go]</u>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This hero\u2019s \u201cKooky Quartet\u201d consisted of him, Quicksilver, Scarlet Witch, and</u></b>  <b><u>Ha</u><u>wkeye. He is considered the successful product of the Weapon I program, also</u> <u>known as</u></b> <b><u>Project: Rebirth. In the</u> </b><em><b><u>Civil War</u> </b></em><b><u>story arc, this man led</u><u> (+) resistance to the Superhero</u> <u>Registration Act. His chief weapon is made from an alloy</u> of steel and vibranium, and his love interest is Sharon Carter. This friend of (*)</b> Bucky Barnes battled the Red Skull before being frozen in ice for decades. For 10 points, name this patriotic Avenger who wields a red, white, and blue shield.", "answer": "<b><u>Captain America</u></b> [or Steve(n) <b><u>Rogers</u></b>; prompt on \u201cCap\u201d] [Saul Hanki<u>n]</u>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "<b><u>Although this river's source is only 150 miles from shore, it unusually runs for over</u></b> <b><u>sev</u><u>enteen times that length. The Jebba and Kainji Dams produce power from this rive</u><u>r. Its</u></b> <b><u>oil-rich delta is home to cities such as</u><u> (+) Port Harcourt. The Mandinka people live in this</u> <u>river's basin, which was explored by</u> Mungo Park. Timbuktu, the center of the (*) </b>Mali Empire, lies on this river. For 10 points, name this West African river that gives its name to two countries, including the most populous country in Africa.", "answer": "<b><u>Niger</u></b> River [do not accept \u201cthe Nigeria River\u201d]  [Kenji Goli<u>mlim]</u>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "<b><u>The Las Limas figure produced by this culture depicts a youth holding a were-</u><u>jag</u><u>uar. The Cascajal [cass-cuh-HALL] Block may demonstrate evidence of a (+)</u></b> <b>written <u>language among these people. These people's first major site emerged during the</u> Early Formative Period. Their most notable artifacts may have been converted thrones and typically wear leather helmets, and can be found at sites like (*)</b> La Venta and San Lorenzo. This civilization's name comes from the Nahuatl [nah-wah-tell] word for \"rubber people\". For 10 points, name this Mesoamerican civilization that created colossal stone heads.", "answer": "<b><u>Olmec</u></b>s  [Mike Bentl<u>ey]</u>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man\u2019s reputation was hurt by a Chenango County trial in which he stood accused</u></b> <b><u>of f</u><u>raudulent gold-digging. Lilburn Boggs\u2019 \u201cextermination order\u201d drove him from</u></b> <b><u>Missouri to Illinois, where he renamed the city of \u201cCommerce\u201d after the</u><u> (+) Hebre</u>w word for \u201cBeautiful Place.\u201d A mob in Carthage, Illinois murdered this founder of (*)</b> Nauvoo along with his brother Hyrum in 1844. In 1823, the angel Moroni guided this man to a set of  \u201cgolden plates\u201d in Reformed Egyptian. For 10 points, name this founder of Mormonism.", "answer": "Joseph <b><u>Smith</u></b>, Jr.  [Matt Bollinger]", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>The policy that began under this act ended in 1934 with the passage of the Wheeler-</u></b> <b><u>Ho</u><u>ward Law, although a similar version of this law continued in Alaska until 1993. Th</u><u>is</u></b> <b><u>act was upheld as a valid exercise of plenary power in</u><u> (+)</u> </b><em><b><u>Lone Wolf v</u></b></em><b><u>.</u></b><em><b><u> Hitchcock</u></b></em><b><u>. The</u> <u>Burke Act amended this act to defer citizenship offers</u> to the end of a 25-year probation period after which trust patents would be validated. This act resulted in the (*)</b> \u201ccheckerboarding\u201d of many reservations. For 10 points, name this 1887 act that called for the surveying and allotment of communal lands held by Native tribes.", "answer": "<b><u>Dawes</u></b> Severalty Act of 1887  [Zihan Zhen<u>g, ed.</u> Rob Carson]", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man debated against Hugh MacDiarmid on \"Extremism in the Defense of Liberty\"</u></b>  <b><u>at the Oxford Union Society. After this man\u2019s death, his wife raised all six of his daughters</u></b>  <b><u>alone. This man ran Temple Number 7 in</u> (+) Harlem. A week after his home was </b> <b><u>firebombed, this man was shot to death w</u>hile addressing a crowd in Washington Heights. He delivered a speech in Cleveland was called\"The (*) </b>Ballot or the Bullet,\" which followed his earlier break with the Nation of Islam. For 10 points, name this Muslim civil rights leader who advocated black separatism.", "answer": "<b><u>Malcolm X</u></b> [or Malcolm <b><u>Little</u></b>, or El-Hajj Malik El-<b><u>Shabazz</u></b>] [Victor Prie<u>to]</u>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man was the Prime Minister when the common law rules for insanity defenses were</u></b>  <b><u>developed, following Daniel M\u2019Naghten\u2019s murder of this man\u2019s private secretary Edward</u></b>  <b><u>Drummond. This man precipitated the</u>(+) Bedchamber Crisis when he demanded the </b> <b>removal of Whigs from Queen Victoria\u2019s personal retinue. His Tamworth Manifesto </b> <b>organized the (*) </b>Conservative Party, and he attempted to use the Irish potato famine as a reason to repeal the Corn Laws. For 10 points, name this British Prime Minister who lends his first name to the London police force.", "answer": "Robert <b><u>Peel</u> </b> [Matt Weiner]", "metadata": "History - European History"}], "bonuses": []}